So there's silica up
on the upper right.
Can you see that?
So fused silica, that's
basically almost quartz.
That's basically quartz.
So you are really close
to making a nice crystal,
but notice how high of viscosity
you have versus temperature.
Notice that you're at this very,
very high value for viscosity.
It's a really thick material.
And people care a
lot about viscosity
when they work with glass.
Why?
Because you need to
know, for example,
is the viscosity at a point
where I can work with it?
Can I shape it?
That's the bottom.
That's the region that
says working range.
I can still shape it.
I can make a window.
There it flows under
its own weight.
So now I can shape it and
it will lose the shape.
That's kind of important to know
if I'm making a glass animal.
There its stress can
still be relieved.
Remaining stress can
still be relieved,
and up there you
can rapidly cool it
without introducing new defects.
But look at the tradeoff
between the temperature
that you have to go to and the
viscosity and the viscosity
that you have.
So if you go now from
this almost quartz
all the way down--
OK, there you take a little
bit of stuff and you put it in,
but it's still 96% silica.
And now you go to
boiled silicate.
Remember, it's like 75%, 80%
silica plus other additives.
And look at how much you've
changed the temperature.
So I can now work
with this material
below 1,000 C. That has huge
consequences for industry,
for actually making
different things out
of glass, which we
now do regularly.
And the Romans did it too,
but they didn't know why.
They said, well, if you add
a little bit of this dirt,
something different happens.
Let's try a little
bit of that one.
Now we know.
We know why.